焦点影片
制  作  公  司
康  卡  斯  特  旗  下  公  司
西   拉   影    业
丹佛与黛利拉公司
出    品
焦 点 电 影 公 司
出      品
联 合 出 品
西 拉 影 业
丹 佛 与 黛 利 拉 影 业 出 品
姑 娘 警 察 公 司
TGIM 影 业
87/11 公 司
联 合 出 品
导 演
大 卫 · 里 奇
在 28 年 后 的 1989 年 11 月，
柏 林 墙 倒 塌，冷 战 结 束。
不                  是
但 这 不 是
我 们 的 故 事
不        是
不                         是
柏 林
年
月
克格勃-前苏联国家安全委员会
不     是
伦 敦
不         是
天 后
伏特加
查
塞隆
理兹
麦卡沃伊
詹
姆斯
古德曼
约
翰
施威格
蒂
尔
马森
埃
迪
波多拉
索
菲亚
罗
默勒
兰
约
豪克尔
翰内斯
约翰内森
詹
福克纳
姆斯
巴
苏科瓦
巴拉
琼斯
托
比
玛丽•范莉亚
马里索尔•龙卡丽
选角导演
尤狄克•基梅尼
大卫•闵可夫斯基
联合制片人
安东尼•约翰斯顿
杰夫•摩朗尼
联合制片人
弗雷德里克•桑德尔
安东尼•缪尔
联合执行制片人
约翰•霍利汉
音乐总监
泰勒•贝茨
音乐原创
辛蒂•伊万斯
服装设计
伊莉莎柏特•罗纳尔兹多迪尔
剪辑
大卫•索里曼
艺术指导
乔纳森•塞拉
摄影导演
乔•诺伊玛克
史蒂文•斯卡斐利
执行制片人
伊森•史密斯
大卫•格拉德
柯特•约翰斯塔德
执行制片人
尼克•迈耶
马克•沙贝尔格
执行制片人
埃瑞克•吉特尔
彼得•什未林
制片人
凯利•麦考密克
查理兹•塞隆
A.J.迪克斯
贝丝•科莫
制片人
改编自ONI出版社                                       漫画小说“ 最冷的城市 ”
文字:安东尼·约翰斯顿  和                                        漫画:山姆·哈特
改编自ONI出版社 漫画小说“ 最冷的城市 ”
文字:安东尼•约翰斯顿  和  漫画:山姆•哈特
库尔特·约恩斯塔德
编剧
大卫·里奇
导演
极寒
之城
诚意出品
不               是
事 件 回 溯
最高机密
姓名:
詹姆斯·加斯科涅
斯塔西：前东德国家安全部
机                        密
机           密
姓名：                                             不详
代号：                                      小望远镜
所属机构：                                  斯塔西
机                        密
姓名：
驻地：
所属机构：
尤里·巴赫金
莫斯科，柏林
克格勃
克格勃-前苏联国家安全委员会
机                        密
姓名：
驻地：
所属机构：
尤里·巴赫金
莫斯科，柏林
克格勃
机                               密
姓名：                          尤里·巴赫金
驻地：                        莫斯科，柏林
所属机构：                           克格勃
姓名:
大卫·珀西瓦尔
驻地:
柏林
所属机构:
军情六处
军情六处-英国陆军情报六局
机                               密
东    柏    林
营业中
钱好 但是情报更好
你给我带了什么情报?
不                        是
西   柏   林
坦 佩 尔 霍 夫 中 央 机 场
苏联贸易代表团
CCCP-为俄语的苏联简写
UdSSR为德语的苏联简写
不                        是
东 柏 林
这里发生什么事?
布雷莫维奇先生
这些人昨晚被抓到在开派对
东德最优秀最聪明的人
你
过来!
我说过来
过来
要找乐子是吧?
那咱们就来点有趣的
这是什么?
来啊 来跳舞
音乐响起了
给他来点掌声
昨晚有个家伙在这里
一个叛徒
告诉我他在哪里
巴赫金 在哪里?
名单在哪里?
他没露过面 布雷莫维奇同志
资本主义的败类 他会卖掉名单的
找到他! 我要拿到名单
鲍里斯 照片给我
注意看
这人是叛徒
认识吗?
法 医 研 究 所
柏            员
柏林警务专员
请         心
请小心!
快速通过
西柏林
中 央 咖 啡 馆
晚上好 女士
你以为我是瑞典人吗?
大卫·哈塞尔霍夫-霹雳游侠主演
硬币街
电 影 国 际
潜 行 者
我不确定 但我想就是她
她现在在去亚历山大广场的路上
把她抓过来
潜 行 者
你跟我走
你疯了吗
他就只想谈谈
潜 行 者
这   个   电   话
可   改   变   你
这个电话可能
会改变你的一生
每日新闻
个 人 档 案
重要记录 请妥善保管
萨切尔
双  面  间  谍
禁止进入
机                   密
东 德
布雷莫维奇说那个叛徒就在那栋楼里
保持警惕
你现在必须听妈妈的话
做个坚强的女孩儿
他们刚从楼里出来了
40米了 还在靠近
我看到他们了
怎么回事?
我看不到他们了
我也看不见
谁能看见他们? 回话
人太多了
我开了一枪
打中目标了吗?
看不清楚 我们得转移了
全是雨伞 我什么也看不见
用无线电呼叫支援
正在努力
快点
她在这儿 速来支援
不要
别开枪
受死吧 臭婊子
站住 你们在这干什么呢?
请等一下
把手放到脑后
趴到地上
马上趴下
洛林
不                        是
三 天 后
我需要用车
您好啊 大使
谢谢你
请节哀
萨切尔同志
布雷莫维奇同志
名单
乖女孩
请允许我
今晚我们一醉方休
你没开玩笑?
有那么一刻我认为你想杀了我
珀西瓦尔告诉我你的真实身份了
干这行
就要准备随时进尸体袋
不         是
巴 黎
剧               终
东德和西德
East and West..
并非因为彼此有武装而互相猜疑
Do not mistrust each other because we are armed..
恰恰是因为我们互相猜疑
We are armed...
我们才不得不武装起来
because we mistrust each other.
戈尔巴乔夫先生
Mr Gorbachev,
拆掉这堵墙
Tear down this wall.
天哪
Oh my God...
该死的詹姆斯·加斯科涅
James fuckin' Gascoigne...
你是怎么找到我的?
How did you find me?
你他妈还以为自己间谍当的挺好的吧
Maybe you're not as good at this spy shit as you think.
是萨切尔对吗?
It was Satchel, wasn't it?
萨切尔出卖了我
Satchel gave me up.
我一直认为应该由最好的特工解决我
I always thought if I got tackled by the best,
但是巴赫金 你不是最好的
But you're not the best, are you Bakhtin?
你就是个克格勃的混蛋
You're the biggest fucking cunt in the KGB.
尽管骂吧 吉米
Sticks and stones, Jimmy.
你的黑眼圈看起来不太妙啊
That's an nasty black eye.
C首长人呢?
Where is C.?
考虑到最近的发生的事 这次审讯他是不会露面的
Given the scale of recent world events he will not be joining us.
是啊 当然了
Yes of course.
以下被录音人员 我自己 高级督察 埃里克·格雷警官
The voices on record are the following, myself, Senior Director and Officer Eric Gray,
我们的美国客人埃米特·库兹费德
Our American guest Emmett Kurzfeld,
来自美国中情局
The US CIA,
和英国特工洛林·布劳顿
entertaining British operational officer Lorraine Broughton.
在我们开始之前 我可以正式请求
Before we begin, so may I formally request that
库兹费德先生退出这次任务汇报吗?
Mr. Kurzfeld be removed form the debriefing.
不能
Request denied.
那我得告诉你 不要说中情局来这里
Then I have to tell you, says not for the CIA to here.
洛林 这次主要汇报人是你
Lorraine, you're the subject of this debriefing.
但你不是管事的  我明白
Not it's controller. I understand.
我当时在柏林
I was there in Berlin.
我在此全权代表中情局
And I'm here with the full executive authority of Langley.
本来为了让你好受一点
Could have make you more comfortable,
我可以和他们一起躲到玻璃后面
I could stand behind the mirror with everybody else.
不巧那边挤了点
But it's a little crowded there.
婊子养的
Cock sucker..
你说什么?
What did you say?
没说什么
I didn't say anything.
洛林 你刚说什么了?
I'm sorry, did you say something, Lorraine?
你听见我说什么了?  我知道你说了
Did your hear me say something? I thought you said something.
她说什么了?
What did she say?
啊?
What?
额..
Now...
你可以把录像带倒回去听听啊
Do you want to play the tape back?
好吧
Well then.
我们可以开始了吗
Shall we begin?
柏林那边
Berlin.
到底发生了什么事?
What happened?
是啊
And...
柏林
Hm, Berlin...
妈的
Fuck..
你好 洛林
Ah, Lorraine,
抱歉这么着急把你叫来
Sorry to bring you in a such short notice.
你认识C首长吧?
You know C.
认识  我们刚刚看了你的档案
Yes. We were just going over your file.
知道你俄语很棒
I see your Russian is excellent.
懂得如何脱身
You expert in escape and evasion.
精通情报收集
Proficient in intelligence collection
擅长近身肉搏战
and hand to hand combat.
你所掌握的技能真是让人印象深刻啊
It is an impressive set of skills.
跟我一样 很了解苏联人
Knowing the Reds as I do,
想完成任务她得使出浑身解数了
she'll need to use every damn one of them.
那我就直接切入主题了
I will get straight to the point
你对詹姆斯.加斯科涅了解多少?
How well do you know James Gascoigne?
知道一点
Enough to say hello.
我们85年在伊斯坦布尔一起工作过
We worked together in Istanbul in 85.
他死了
He is dead.
他昨晚在柏林执行任务时被杀害
Gascoigne was killed last night on a mission in Berlin.
今天早上西德警察把他的尸体从河里打捞出来
West German police fished his body out of the street this morning.
并且从他身体里取出一枚7.62毫米的托卡列夫手枪子弹
And the coronary extracted a 7.62 mm Tokarev round...
刺穿头骨
From the base of the skull.
苏联人干的
Soviets..
昨天加斯科涅会见了一位斯塔西的军官
Yesterday.. Gascoigne met with a Stasi officer,
代号"小望远镜"
code named Spyglass.
我们承诺给小望远镜提供豁免权,以此来交换一个缩微胶卷中的文件
We promised Spyglass immunity in exchange for a document on microfilm..
我们称它为“名单”
Codenamed "The list".
这份名单藏在一个瑞士手表里
Hidden in a Swiss watch.
名单上有所有秘密活跃的官员名字
The list contains every active clandestine officer.
和所有见不得人的交易
All the shady deals..
信息量极大
It's an atomic bomb of information
足以让冷战再延续四十年
that could extend the cold war for another forty years,
我们认为现在名单在杀害加斯科涅的那个杀手手里
And we believe that the man that killed Gascoigne, now has it.
我们的消息来源指向尤里·巴赫金
Our sources point to Yuri Bakhtin,
此人是克格勃机构的头牌杀手 手上有几十条人命
KGB hatchet man with more than a dozen confirmed kills.
所以你要派我去莫斯科?
So, you want me in Moscow?
不
No.
巴赫金并没上飞机
Bakhtin never got on the flight.
所以他和那个名单都还在柏林
So he's still in Berlin along with the list.
所有人都在找他 美国佬和法国方面
Everyone is hunting for it, the Yankees, the Frogs.
苏联方面  当然还有我们的人 珀西瓦尔
Soviets, and Cruzes.. And our man, Percival
珀西瓦尔是谁?  大卫·珀西瓦尔
Who is Percival? David Percival.
他是我们在柏林的一号特工
He is our number one in Berlin.
也是你的联络人
He is your point of contact.
这可是上好的香水
Straight from the teat of the Virgin Mary.
搞到这东西不容易
Jordache wasn't easy.
这是我给我妻子准备的生日礼物
It's for my wife's birthday.
很好 现在告诉我名单在哪里
That's very nice, now where is that fucking list?
我昨晚把胶片给加斯科涅了
I gave the microfilm to Gascoigne last night.
他并没有出现
James didn't show up.
我已经做了我该做的 把名单给他了
I did my part I gave him the list.
你必须把我和我家人送走 我们在这里不安全
You have to get me and my family across this. Not safe for us anymore here.
俄国人盯上我了
The Russian's are onto me.
没有名单 免谈
No list, no deal.
我可是豁出去了啊  没有名单 免谈
I risked everything. No list, no deal..
听着小望远镜 没拿到名单
You listen to me Spyglass without that list...
我完全可以把你拉出去一枪毙了你
Why shouldn't I take you outside and shoot you in the fucking head?
你敢杀一名斯塔西官员?
You are going to kill a stasi officer?
对于你这种要投奔西德的 是的
One that's about to defect to the west, yeah.
没有大使馆照顾
Without an embassy to look after him
珀西瓦尔 什么都要靠自己 和当地人差不多了
Percival has gone somewhat native.
狂傲不逊
And fucking feral,
柏林局势混乱
Berlin is the Wild West.
要是那该死的墙倒塌 我们可不想被埋在下面
If that bloody wall comes crashing down we don't want to be under it.
要是苏联方面得到名单 我们都要被盯上了
If the Russians get that list, we're all bugged.
这就被动了
Side ways.
你的新身份是伊丽莎白·劳埃德
You are Elisabeth Loyd.
一位毕业于剑桥的律师 受詹姆斯.加斯科涅家人所托
A Cambridgeeducated lawyer, sent by James Gascoinge's family
去取回他们刚去世的儿子的尸体和遗物
to retrieve the body and the effects of their recently deceased son.
你的任务就是找到珀西瓦尔
Your mission is to connect with Percival
不惜一切代价拿回名单
and do whatever it takes to get that list home.
记住 洛林
And remember Lorraine...
这是敏感时期
This is highly sensitive..
不要相信任何人
Trust no one.
跟我走 快
Follow me! Come, come, come.
这边 快点
Quickly, this way.
你说你有备份了  我都背下来了
You told me you made a copy. I memorized it.
都背下来了? 所有人的名字?
You memorized it? Every single agent on that list?
你每周三都会去竹篙巷妓院
Every wednesday you visit the Penny lane brothel..
你最喜欢的姑娘是玛戈特 她真名叫玛丽亚
Your favorite girl is Margot, her real name is Maria.
玛丽亚?
Maria?
好 我会带你离开这儿  你是个好人 珀西瓦尔
Alright, I will get you across. You're a good man, Percival.
少废话
Fuck off.
我只想要得到名单 只要我一拿到 哦 妈的
I just want the list. Once I've... oh fuck.
站住!   我会联系你
Halt! I'll be in touch.
晚上好 警官  晚上好请出示证件
Good night, officers. Goodnight document please.
证件  哦 好
Document... Oh, yeah..
瞧见了?
You saw it?
快点 这边！
Quick, this way!
起开
Get up!
我迟到了
Oh, I'm so fucking late.
欢迎来到坦佩尔霍夫机场
Welcome to Tempelhof airport
布劳顿小姐
Miss Broughton,
珀西瓦尔先生迟到了 他叫我来接你
Mr. Percival was running late, he sent me to pick you up..
有行李吗?  没有 已经送到住处了
Check bags? No, they have been sent.
跟我走吧
Please follow me.
这里禁止停车
No parking in the terminal.
只装卸
Loading and unloading only..
第一次来柏林吗?  是的
So, is this your first time in Berlin? Yes.
来的真是时候
Well, it's remarkable time to be here.
美妙的音乐 超级棒的夜生活
Wonderful music, superb nightlife.
美味的餐馆
Marvelous restaurants.
你必须到中央咖啡馆去喝一杯
You must try the Central Cafe for a drink.
你待会需要它
You will need it later.
你记得布雷莫维奇先生吧?
You remember Mr. Bremovych don't you?
你当然记得
Of course you do.
他很好奇你来柏林的目的
Well he's very curious..what you are doing here in Berlin
你在干什么啊?
What the hell are you doing?
欢迎来到柏林 我是大卫
Welcome to Berlin, I'm David...
你他妈死哪里去了?
Where the fuck were you?
别开枪 我拿着你的鞋子呢
Don't shoot. I have got your shoe.
我帮你拿行李
Let me help you with your bags.
我的天  妈的
Come on Fuck's sake.
苏联人真他妈重
Russians are fucking heavy.
我才下飞机5分钟 身份就暴露了
Five minutes on the ground, and I'm already made,
你没暴露
You are not made..
他们知道我的名字  这就麻烦了
They knew my name. That's troubling.
还有你的名字  哇哦,出乎意料
And yours. Probably surprising.
真是个不错的开始 珀西瓦尔
Great fucking start, Percival.
你对他的第一印象如何?
Well what was your first impression?
你说大卫吗?
Of David?
他很帅 三十几岁
He was handsome, late thirties.
有着和奥康纳一样的头发
Disastrous Sinnade O'Connor hair.
那是个爱尔兰歌手
Irish singer.
我问他在那里如何生存
I asked him what the deal was and he said...
他说尽量融入当地人的生活
Is to blend in.
你想摸摸吗?
You wanna touch it?
让自己看起来像当地人一样
To blend in the east.
我当时正沿着门口跑
I was running by gate by the way. I mean, how the fuck,
那些犹太人怎么会认为你会帮我找回名单?
does the Jews think that you're gonna be able to help me find that list?
只要你去认领加斯科涅的尸体
As soon as you pick up Gascoingne's body,
他们就会注销你的护照 明天用第一班飞机把你遣送出境
They will null and void your visa and you'll be on the first flight back home.
我自有办法   那是查利检查站
I'll figure it out. That's Checkpoint Charlie.
我办公室就在那边
My office is back there.
我不是来这儿搜集明信片的
I'm not here to collect postcards, Percival.
我的酒店就转角处 在那下车
Just drop me at my hotel, it's around the corner.
你不是说你之前没来过柏林吗?
I thought you said you had never been to Berlin before.
难道我不会看地图吗?
I can read a fucking map!
一分钟就看懂地图了
That will just take a minute.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
给法西斯猪一个警告
Sending a message to a fascist pig.
替我向布雷莫维奇同志问好
Say hello to Comrade Bremovych for me.
今晚的柏林高度警戒
Tensions are high in East Berlin tonight,
因为公民抗议行为势头不减
as civil disobedience continues to build momentum.
警方用催泪瓦斯和水枪镇压示威人群
These berlin youth leaders shout out their protest..
这些柏林青年仍然大声表达自己的抗议
Through tear gas and water cannons
并有多起报道说警察
and there are numerous reports of police
用警棍殴打和平示威者
beating peaceful demonstrators with batons.
我是来取一位英国公民的尸体的
I have been sent to arrange the return of a British subject.
尸体是通过身体组织鉴定的
The body was identified by a tissue.
我相信
Yes. I believe so.
这不是一个问题
This was not a question.
这是个声明
It was a statement.
他是你同事?
He was your colleague?
不在同一部门
Different department.
他是哪个部门的  不是跟我一个部门的
Which department? A different one.
你有转移尸体的授权书吗?
Do you have the transfer papers?
你们知道那些电影吗 画面渐渐慢下来
Do you know those movies where the picture just starts to slow down...
融化
and melt..
然后燃烧
Then get fire...
哇
Wow...
柏林的日子就像那种电影一样
That's Berlin.
护照号码是错的
The passport number is incorrect.
如果不提供准确信息的话我是不会让你带走尸体的
I will not release this body without the right information.
这个错误没什么大不了的
It's a simple mistake.
罗伊德女士 在德国 我们从不会犯这种低级的错误
Miss Loyd, in Germany we don't make simple mistakes.
我实话实说 你让我吃了一惊
I am not gonna lie. I'm impressed.
敢跑到我这来 胆子得够大
You have got some balls breaking in here!
那你得看看我的蛋蛋 你会更吃惊的
You should see my balls then you will be really impressed.
我记住你这句话了
I will take your word for it.
我知道你找到了留在德国的办法
I see you've found a way to stay,
你把16天的签证时长改成了76天
You are at 16 when you feel it's 76.
没错
That's right.
我哪儿也不去
I am not going anywhere.
我至少在这呆一周
I'm here for at least another week.
我他妈的太幸运了
Lucky fucking me.
他们现在是不会交出尸体的 除非他们解开谜团 找到真相
They won't release his body now, till they investigated that right through a nightmare.
你到底怎么进来的?
How the fuck did you get in here?
我呆在柏林很久了 我应该认识几乎所有还不错的宾馆
You know, I've been in Berlin a long time, and I think I know every doormen..
的看门人
Of every decent shithouse
还有柏林墙两边还算不错的妓院
borderlined decent brothels on both sides of the wall.
那你肯定认识小望远镜
Well then you must know Spyglass.
我从来没见过他
Never met the fella.
他是詹姆斯的人
He was James'
从机场就一直跟着我的那个女人 你了解她的情况吗?
What do you know about this woman who's been following me since Templehof?
我不得不说 你真的太有魅力
I'd say that you're an attractive woman...
然后你得自己想想为什么了
and you should do the math.
你知道的如果是我跟踪你 我说认真的
You know, if I was to follow you, I mean, properly
你永远不会发现
you'd never fuckin know.
跟踪是有技巧的
There's a knack to it, isn't there?
就像走钢丝 吹风笛一样
It's like walking a tightrope or playing the bagpipes.
你可能很快就轻车熟路 也可能一辈子都学不会
You can either do it, or you can't.
随便你
Knock yourself out.
我想买块表
I'd like to purchase a watch.
我需要获取东德情报网的权限
I need access to a network in East Berlin.
明天关门之前再来
Come back tomorrow before closing.
尽管共产党官员尽力维持秩序
East Berlin.. Is on a short fuse again tonight,
但今晚东德再一次举行游行示威
as communist party officials struggled to maintain order.
你了解詹姆斯多少?
How well do you know James Gascoigne?
他死了
He is dead.
验尸官在头盖骨底部
The coronary extracted a 7.62mm Tokarev
取出7.62毫米托卡列夫手枪子弹
around in the base of his skull.
苏联人干的
Soviets
我们知道萨切尔是谁
We know who Satchel is.
我们必须离开
We need to run.
你想在加斯科涅的公寓里找到名单吗?
You expected to find the list in Gascoigne's apartment?
你没有意识到你已经太迟了吗?
You realized you were late to the party?
珀西瓦尔还有那些俄罗斯人肯定已经抢先搜查过了
Percival, the Russians, everybody must have already ransacked the place.
是的
Yes.
我们的问题不只是那份名单
But the list wasn't our only problem.
我去柏林之前 你还告诉过我一件事
Before I left, you told me one last thing.
这就是我为什么我不希望中情局的人在场
This is exactly why I didn't want the CIA present.
小望远镜透露 这份名单
Spyglass revealed that this list..
会使一个代号为萨切尔的双重间谍暴露身份
Would expose a double agent by the name of Satchel.
无论是死是活 我要见到萨切尔
I want Satchel, dead or alive.
这个叛徒多年来都是我们的眼中钉
This traitor's been a thorn in our side for years.
他败坏了我们的名声
He is a black eye to the Crown.
这也是军情六处有史以来最大的一起情报泄露案件
And the single biggest intelligence leak in MI6 history.
你必须得找到这个叫萨切尔的混蛋
You expose this bastard Satchel.
要不然我们就判决你犯下叛国罪 执行绞刑
We'll hang you for treason.
然后你就可能发现自己坐在白金汉宫喝茶
You might find yourself taking tea in Buckingham Palace.
所以
So no.
我并不只是在加斯科涅的公寓里找那份名单
I wasn't just looking for the list in Gascoigne's apartment.
前进 把她抓回来
Go ahead, bring her back.
小心点
Take action.!
我和珀西瓦尔对合作的定义明显不一样
Percival and I seem to have a different definition for collaboration.
在第三层  快上楼
In the third floor. Quickly the stairs!
这是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
只有他知道我去了加斯科涅的公寓
He was the only one who knew I was going to Gascoigne's apartment.
如果我发现他报警了
If I knew he was going to call the police,
我会换身装束
I would have worn a different outfit.
换身装束..
Different outfit...
快点 我看到了
Quick. I saw something.
喂!站住!
Hey! halt!
街上出现了越来越多追求改变的呼声
With repeated calls for change on the streets
这使示威者更加有信心
and the protestors going ever more confident..
留给东德政府的时间已经不多了
Time is running out for the east German governtment.
人们普遍认为 由共产党执政的局面
Popular opinion has it that the Communist.
不会持续太久
Claim to leadership can't be upheld much longer.
如果还没有改变
And if rapid change is not forthcoming..
那么今天相对平静的抗议
Today's relatively calm protest..
就会是暴风雨前的宁静
Could be seen as the calm before the storm.
人们要求的不仅是换一个新的领导人
It's not just new faces that recalled for..
或许还想彻底拆除柏林墙
But perhaps a complete demolition of the wall.
外套给我吧
Let me take your coat.
别太拘束
Make yourself at home..
我的天
Fucking yeah!
喝杜松子酒吗?
You want a pair of Jeans?
请自便
Help yourself.
你的图书馆里竟然有拉里·弗林特的色情书
Your library includes Larry Flynt.
言论自由的追求者嘛
Champion of free to speech.
你怎么看巴赫金的?
What did you find on Bakhtin?
如果巴赫金想要俄罗斯人拿到那份名单
Look if Bakhtin.. Wanted the Russians to have that list,
那么现在他早就给他们了
he would have given it to them by now.
你只要等他进一步的活动
You just have to wait for him to make his move.
我等不及了
I can't afford to wait.
珀西瓦尔 这是你的地盘
This is your city, Percival.
但是你居然只认识些看门的和些妓女
But you only know doormen and belhoffs.
所以你在加斯科涅的公寓里找到了什么?
So what did you find in Gascoigne's apartment?
一些标记
Some Doich marks.
空白的护照 签证
Empty passports, visas.
还有几年前你们俩的合照
And a picture of two of you.. together a few years back.
我没说过我们是朋友吗?
Did I not mention that we were friends?
没有  没有?
No. No?
我可能忘说了
I must have forgotten.
那就当我现在告诉你了吧
There you go love.
我要去走走
I'm down for a walk.
我们都在那个名单上
Look, we are all exposed by that list.
拯救世界虽然很酷
Saving the world is cool and all that...
但是我的目标是保住自己的性命
but my main objective is staying alive.
我驻扎德国10年了
I have been held up in Berlin stationed for 10 years,
你要知道我是这里唯一一个能帮你拿到那份名单的人
you have got to know I am the only man in this town who can help you get that list.
没错 我看过你的档案
Yes, I've read your file.
我也看了你的档案
I've also read your DOG file.
那我们就别废话了
So let's cut the crap.. shall we?
你整天喝的酩酊大醉 疯疯癫癫 我不知道你真实的一面是什么样子
This whole hungover, sheer play, don't know which way is up act..
但是我不会轻易上当的
I am not buying it.
到现在为止我还是相信你 但是我也可以随时抛弃你
I trust you but far as I can throw you.
欺骗欺人者 其乐无穷
"It's a double pleasure to deceive the deceiver".
你书架上有本尼克洛·马基雅维利的书
Nicola Maquiavelo. It was on your shelf.
天哪 我想我爱上你了  非常遗憾
Oh, my God, I think I fucking love you. That's too bad.
如果关于巴赫金的事 珀西瓦尔说的都是真话
If Percival.. Was telling the truth about Bakhtin,
我得查出俄罗斯人知道了什么
I needed to figure out what the Russians knew.
来一杯斯托尼酒 加冰
Stoney on ice.
我今晚不说德语
I am not speaking German tonight.
所以那你是英国人
So you're British.
我记住你了
Very impressive.
这绝不是你唯一的天赋
This can't be your only talent.
天才是会被高估的
Talents can be overrated.
但能尽心尽力办事又忠心耿耿的人是越来越少见了
But dedication and loyality is very rare these days.
这里的每个人都在找某样东西
Everyone here searching for something.
你在找什么?
What are you looking for?
说了这么多
When all said and done..
你还不如说 我们所有人实际上找得都是同一件东西
Wouldn't you say deep down we're all just searching for the same thing..
我让您一个人呆了会
I leave you alone for only a moment...
您就有仰慕者了?
and already you are attracting admirers.
先生 三个人本来也可以的
Mossier, three is not always a crowd.
但是今晚不行
But tonight it is.
法国小姐 你又来了啊
French women
那这位英国小姐怎么想的呢?
What about the British?
或许我们可以达成一些协议?
Maybe we can make some sort of arrangement?
我们太久没见了
We haven't seen each other in a long time,
所以得好好聊聊
and we really need to catch up.
单独谈谈
Alone.
女士们 柏林是个小地方
Ladies, Berlin is a small place.
我想我们会再见面的
I'm sure our paths will cross again.
抱歉
Sorry.
你看起来需要帮助
You looked like you needed saving.
多谢你的好意 还请问女士你叫?
Well I appreciate the gesture, Miss...?
拉萨尔
Lasalle...
德尔菲娜·拉萨尔
Delphine Lasalle.
很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet you.
所以 德尔菲娜 你是做什么的?
So, what do you do, Delphine?
我是兼职口译者
I am a parttime translator.
但我更想当个诗人
Who really wants to be a poet...
或者是个摇滚巨星
maybe a rock star.
我的朋友在附近有家俱乐部
My friend owns a club nearby.
你想去吗?
Wanna come check it out?
现在?  是啊
Now? Sure.
我不能
I can't.
好吧 反正我给你个地址
Well, I'll give you the address anyway.
明晚在那不见不散
Come meet me there tomorrow night.
你会来吗?
Will you come?
也许吧
Maybe?
你很执着啊
You are relentless.
是啊
Oui..
大卫·哈塞尔霍夫在城里
David Hasselhof is in town.
我们很幸运
Lucky us.
柏林真的完了
Berlin is truly doomed..
你的手表准备好了
Your watch is ready.
在桌上的信封里
It's on that counter, in that plain envelop.
我相信你肯定会觉得我的线人非常棒
I think you will find my contact very useful.
你的手表准备好了
Your watch is ready.
在桌上的信封里
It's on that counter. In that plain envelop.
我相信你肯定会觉得我的线人非常棒
I think you will find my contact very useful.
东德人在本周早些时候
East Berliners stormed the West Germany embassies in
闯进捷克斯洛伐克的西德大使馆
Czechoslovakia early at this week...
现在捷克政府下令 在边境站处
As the Czech government has began to waive the refugees
不必问难民太多问题 尽快放行
through checkpoints with few questions.
公众不禁疑惑 东德政府这样还能持续多久
One has to ask how long the East Berlin government can hold on..
巴赫金和名单还没出现在西德
Bakhtin and the list had not yet surfaced in the west.
我要和我的新线人见面谈谈
I needed to meet my new contact.
看看我在东德到底要对付谁
And see what I was up against in the east.
你应该申请访问资格
You should have applied for a visit experiment.
你从事的是什么工作?
What kind of work do you do?
法律事务
Legal affairs..
如果你在六点之前没回来
If you do not return before 6'o clock..
你就会被逮捕 清楚了吗?
You will be arrested. Did you understand?
我知道了
I understand.
现在我还是不是很相信你的故事
Right now I'm not feeling very confident of this story of yours.
为什么在东德不用珀西瓦尔的线人
Why not use Percival's connections in the East?
你告诉过我
You told me...
不要相信任何一个人
To trust no one.
你好
Hello.
快点 这边!
Go ahead, on the side!
你迟到了
You are late.
还被人跟踪
And you were followed.
我迟到就是因为我被人跟踪了
I'm late because I was followed.
20分钟之前 我在共和国广场附近 刚甩掉他们
I lost them 20 minutes ago near the Piazza della Republic.
你还真有两下子啊
You're as good as your reputation.
你确定在这见面最好吗?
Are you sure this is the best place to meet?
在敌人的眼皮底子下
Keep your enemies close.
最危险的地方就是最安全的地方
I am a permanent fixture for them now.
钟表匠说 这些天在黑市
The watchmaker says there has been great interest in this list..
有很多人对这份名单感兴趣
...In the black market the last few days.
有巴赫金的消息了吗?  没有
Any sign of Bakhtin? No.
这个萨切尔让墙两边的人忧心忡忡
This Satchel character, has people worried on both sides of the wall.
没错
Yeah..
你的情报网怎么样?
What kind of network have you assembled?
在墙的这边
There's a lot of dissatisfied youths...
有很多对他们不满意的年轻人
on this side of the wall.
他们就像
They are like uh...
导火索
Tinder books.
只要你找到正确的火花
If you find the right spark...
继续说
keep talking.
我想卖块表
I am interested in selling a watch.
具体说说看
What are you selling?
它非常贵重
It is extremely valuable...
质量很好
Finest quality and...
还装满了秘密
filled with secrets.
介意我先检查一下货物么?
Would you mind if I inspect the merchandise?
我当然介意
Fuck yes, I mind.
你只要告诉有意愿的买家
Just tell potential buyers...
巴赫金有意出售
Bakhtin is open for business.
女士们 柏林是个小地方
Ladies, Berlin is small place.
我想我们会再见面的
I'm sure our paths will cross again.
抱歉
Sorry.
你看起来需要帮助
You looked like you needed saving.
我朋友在附近有家俱乐部
My friend owns a club nereby.
你想来吗?
Wanna come check it out?
我还以为你不会来
I didn't think that you'd show.
斯托尼加冰
Stoney on the rocks.
你记性不错
You pay attention.
我喜欢追求细节
I look for pleasure in the details.
既然我们聊的还不错
Speaking of which...
我真想问你个问题
I have been dying to ask you a question..
我们去个安静点的地方
Let's go someplace quite.
为什么带着枪 德尔菲娜?
Why the gun, Delphine?
你以为你伪装的很好 但实际上很烂
You're not as well disguised as you may think.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你是军情六处的洛林
You are Lorraine Broughton, MI6.
你到这里来就是因为詹姆斯死了
And you are here because of the death of Gascoigne.
关于詹姆斯 你知道些什么事?
What do you know about Gascoigne?
什么也不知道
Nothing.
但是如果有人杀了个盟军的特工
But if someone is killing Allied officers...
我们不都得关注吗?
Shouldn't we all care?
假如人们都愿意
What if it is in that list...?
为了那份名单去厮杀
That's people willing to kill for it.
这是我在法国情报局的第一项任务
It's my first assignment with the French intelligence.
我来这儿只有一年
I've only been here a year.
我害怕了 不行吗?
I'm scared, okay?
当初我接了这项任务是因为觉着很刺激
I got into this because it was exciting,
但是没曾想柏林会变成现在这副模样
But it's never been like this in Berlin.
你应该去当一名诗人的
You should have become a poet.
或去做个摇滚明星
Or a rock star.
所以你和一个法国女特工接上头了
So you made contact with the French operative.
是的
Obviously.
为什么?
Why?
我相信她有我可以利用的情报
I believed she had information I could exploit.
没别的原因
Nothing more.
那她有么?
And did she?
她有什么情报吗 洛林?
Did she have any information, Lorraine?
我得告诉你些事
There's something I need to tell you
和你的朋友珀西瓦尔有关
It has to do with your friend Percival.
洛林
Lorraine...
她有提供任何情报吗 洛林?
Did she have any information, Lorraine?
她给过你情报吗?
She gave you information?
她什么也没给我
She gave me nothing.
他妈的大卫·珀西瓦尔
David fucking Percival.
你跟踪我?
Are you following me?
你他妈还以为自己间谍当的挺好的吧
Maybe you're not as good at this spy shit as you think.
这下是替詹姆斯捅的 你这杂种
That was for James, you fucking prick.
现在把那份该死的名单给我
Now gimme that fucking list.
我们得告诉你一个消息 洛林
We needed to get you a message, Lorraine.
几天过去了 你一点线索都没有
There are several days on to a mission without a single lead.
还旁生许多枝节
And plenty of distractions.
我们必须提醒你发生这些事情的原因
We had to remind you of the cause it had.
哦 我收到你们的消息了
Oh. I received your message.
从这看挺壮观的
That's quite a view.
70英里的铁丝网
70 miles of barbed wire,
310个警戒塔 65条反装甲战壕
310 guard towers, 65 antivehicle trenches,
4万名训练有素全副武装的苏联边防军
40,000 Soviet trained heavily armed frontier troops.
面对这些
All that... and...
居然还有5千多名东德人敢外逃
five thousand GDR citizens still had the brass balls to escape.
你可没少让军情六处操心
You have got the MI6 a worry...
他们甚至找了CIA来帮你
They called the CIA to talk sense into you.
埃里克·格雷给我打了电话
Eric Gray called me.
他当然会打给你的
Of course he did.
不用我多说 你也知道时间紧迫吧
I don't have to remind you of how fast the clock is ticking.
一旦名单曝光
If that thing gets out...
很多辛勤工作的人
a lot of good hard working folks...
不论男女 都会因此而死
brave men and women, are gonna show up dead.
包括你我
You and I included.
我发誓 这几周
I swear to god the last few weeks..
我甚至每天早上一睁开眼就感到恐惧
I dreaded even waking up in the morning.
我知道形势很严峻
I understand the severity of the situations,
时间也很紧迫
and time imperative.
听着 我大老远过来可不是为了给你加油助威的
Listen, I didn't climb all the way up here just to give you some arousing pep talk..
我就直接说重点吧
So I'll cut to the chase.
你昨晚遇到的那个女的
Last night you met a woman.
德尔菲娜·拉萨尔那点儿本事在这可不够看
Delphine Lasalle is out of her depth.
在现在的形势下 我可不希望看到任务执行失败
Given the climate I hate to see an executive order come down the line
不过她可一点也不在乎这个
that falls in her disinterest.
她不在乎?
Her disinterest?
你说她不在乎是什么意思?
What do you mean her disinterest?
这还需要问? 洛林 你能不知道我是什么意思?
Don't insult my intelligence Lorrain. You know exactly what the fuck I mean.
希望你拍张照片留念
Hope you get a snapshot.
下周这儿可就天翻地覆喽
Next week, this will be a whole different picture.
萨切尔已经暴露了
Satchel has been compromised.
到奥兰尼亚街的同性恋酒吧见一面吧
Meet me at the Rough Trade Bar, Oraniastrasse.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
看看隐于夜生活的柏林的另一面
Look at all these hiddenness.
就像个疯狂的美女 我他妈太喜欢这儿了
It's like a beautiful women gone wrong. I fucking love it.
听说巴赫金又出现了
Word is Bakhtin has resurfaced.
警察发现他脑袋上被开了个洞
Cops found him with a homemade lobotomy.
不管怎么样 我们都得解决小望远镜的问题
Either way, we have to deal with Spyglass.
好好想想 他那边也没多少时间了
Thinking it through, he doesn't have much time over there.
我们的首要任务是找到那份名单
Our priority is the list.
我们不能犯错  拜托!
We can't make mistakes. Come on!
我的天 他是我认识的最值得信赖的人 我很少遇到像他这样的
He is hardly the most trustworthy person I've ever met, all the fucking Christ
等下 你说你从来没见过他
Wait, you said you hadn't met him.
我撒谎了
I lied.
他声称 他已经把整张名单都背下来了
And he claimes.. To have memorized the entire list.
他准备叛逃
He is ready to make the jump.
你相信他能记住所有的内容?
You believe he comitted the entire thing to memory?
是的 一字不差
Everything.
早知道是这样 我会把小望远镜放在任务首位
Had I known earlier I would have prioritized Spyglass.
这就意味着 他和那份名单同样重要了
His knowledge made him as valuable as the list.
我们本可以随时带走小望远镜的
We could have grabbed him at any time.
就因为珀西瓦尔一直不告诉我这个情况
Instead Percival kept it a secret,
使我们处于危险境地
putting us in a precarious position.
克格勃会派出手下
Look the KGB are gonna have some very angry bastards out there...
四处寻找小望远镜的下落
...looking for Spyglass.
我们不能按照老规矩或老办法来办这事
We can't trust any of the old rules or methods.
这几天想坐车越境也不是那么难
It's not that difficult to drive across the border these days.
如果你跟小望远镜一样被通缉 越境就难了
It is when you are wanted like Spyglass is!
我们必须在光天化日之下 亲自带他走过边境以确保其安全
We have to walk him across personally to ensure his safety in plain sight
我们要利用明天在亚历山大广场举行的示威游行
We'll use the demonstration tomorrow at the alexanderplatz in plain sight
你简直是疯了  那些示威者们会帮我们分散敌人的注意力
That's insane. All those Protestants will make a great distraction.
小望远镜是由我负责的 我们得按照我的方法去做
Spyglass is my guy. We're gonna do it my way.
好吧
Fine..
但是得用我的关系网搞到越境所需的文件
But we use my contact to get all ours papers are in order.
可以
Alright.
说定了吗?
We have a deal?
不说话我当你同意了
I'll take that as a yes.
你要知道
You see...
那晚我接到了帕西瓦尔的电话 洛林
I received a call from David Percival, that evening, Lorraine.
他说他得到了那份名单
He said he had the list.
给我点时间 让我理解一下
I will need a little time to wrap it up.
他知道萨切尔的真实身份
...and he knew the identity of Satchel.
我已非常接近萨切尔了
Oh, I'm very close to Satchel.
居然没人想告诉我这些?
And no one thought to tell me?
妈的
Fuck!
你带了这么多人来啊
You brought a lot of friends.
我听说巴赫金出了点儿小意外
I heard Bakhtin had a little accident.
我听说他滑倒摔在了一个冰锥上
I heard he slipped and fell on an ice pick.
柏林像是个残忍的女人
Berlin is a cruel mistress.
尤其是对像巴赫金这样的叛徒
Especially for traitors like Bakhtin.
别跟我来共产党那一套 你有麻烦了
Don't be such a fucking communist, you have got a problem.
是的 我知道
Yeah I know.
那份名单在你手上
You have the fucking list.
我们敌对了这么久 都应该知道
We've been in the trenches long enough to know that
如今这世道 柏林有她自己的一套规则
in times like these, Berlin, has its own set of rules.
我可以给你情报
I can give you information...
可以保证双方处于制衡状态
that will keep the balance.
你现在到底跟不跟我合作
Now, are you in or out?
帕西瓦尔想陷害我
Percival is trying to set me up...
你很惊讶?
Are you surprised?
并不是
Not really.
特工之间的合作不过是虚与委蛇
These relationships aren't real.
只是为完成任务的手段罢了
They are just a means to an end.
当你讲真话时 你看起来不一样了
When you tell the truth, you look different.
你的眼神变了
Your eyes change.
谢谢你提醒我
Thanks for the warning.
什么意思?  我的意思是我不会再犯这样的错了
What do you mean? I mean I better not do it again.
为什么?
Why?
因为将来有一天 我可能会为之丧命
Because it's going to get me killed one day.
哇哦 不错哦
Well, I'm impressed.
我还以为默克尔没什么本事呢
Thought Merkel out here was just a good bartender.
你闻起来就像是个斯塔西特工
You smell like a Stasi officer.
刮掉胡子
Shave off the mustache.
用西德产的香皂和香水
Use the soap and colognes from the west.
东德这边的东西你都不能带走
You can't take anything from the east.
默克尔会给你拿些衣服
Merkel will give you some clothes.
这边走 小望远镜先生
Right this way Mr. Spyglass.
这本应该很容易的
It should have been easy.
计划很周全
Plan was sound..
无论是哪出了差错 肯定是有人故意为之
Whatever went wrong did so because someone wanted it to.
而且罪魁祸首还是内部人员
Someone from the inside.
你是被自己人出卖了
You were betrayed by a fellow agent.
你说的是萨切尔
You mean Satchel.
这种事又不是没发生过
Would that be unheard off?
根据您的要求
As per your request.
你并不需要枪
You won't be needing that.
如果他们发现你有枪情况会更糟
It will be worse if they find it on you.
其他的都准备就绪了吗?
Everything else ready?
是的 都是按照您的吩咐办的
Yes, everything you requested.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
你觉着他这衬衫怎么样?
What do you think of his shirt?
我可不想死的时候穿着这件衬衫
I wouldn't be caught dead in it.
但是对他来说挺完美的
But for him it's perfect.
站到这边
Stand over here.
表情自然点儿
Now look like a free man.
这些柏林青年领袖们本周末在亚历山大广场组织了
These Berlin youth leaders have organised
一场示威游行
a demonstration this week at Alexanderplatz.
他是不是跟你说我记住了名单的所有内容?
Did he tell you that I memorized the whole list?
是的
Yes.
我知道对于某些人来说 我并不是那么重要
I realize I may not be as valuable to some people and
甚至有些人想要杀死我 但是...
Some people may even want me dead but...
我能有什么选择?
What choice do I have?
你死了对我一点好处也没有
You are no good to me dead.
而我从未失手过
And I've never lost a package.
我知道
I know.
这是他的家人
It's his family.
这事不在我的计划之中
This was not part of the plan.
我的计划里有
Part of mine.
拜托了
Please.
我负责带走他的妻女
I will take the wife and the kid.
你只需要保护好小望远镜
You will just have to deal with Spyglass.
我不知道护照够不够用
I don't know if I have enough passports.
珀西瓦尔
Percival.
你的王牌特工
Your golden boy..
我爱你
I love you.
我们必须出发了
We have to go.
西德见 祝你好运
See you in the west. Good luck.
我们要自由选举
We want free elections
事先计划里并没有这部分
This was never part of the plan.
我的计划里有
It's part of mine..
别起来
Stay low.
进去
In here.
我们得先给你止血 否则不可能越过边境
We need to deal with this now or we will never get to cross.
我不想死  你不会死的
I don't want to die. You are not going to die.
呆在这
Stay here.
妈的
Fuck!
两个 还有两个
Two more. Just two more.
走
Go!
你需要止血
You need to stop that bleeding...
去找找任何有帮助的东西
Search for anything...
酒 碎布
alcohol, rags.
还敢叫我婊子吗?
Am I a bitch now?
上车
Get in!
你得好好练练德语
You need to work on your German.
讲的太烂了
It's horrible.
我操
Fucking hell.
系上安全带
Fasten your seatbelt.
你没事吧?  我没事
Are you allright? Yeah
我们得走了
We have to go...
太冷了  打开车门
It's so cold! Open your door!
我的脚 卡住了
My foot... It's stuck!
我动不了了  深呼吸
I can't move. Just breathe.
我的腿
My leg!
你需要休息一会儿吗?  不
You need a break? No!
那么
So...
好吧 我想我知道全过程了
Yes, I think I understand everything.
你制定了计划
You made your plan.
但却失败了
You failed to get the...
你没能把这位极度重要的情报人员安全带到西德
high value asset safely across to the west.
你他妈把我派进了一个马蜂窝里
You sent me in to a fucking hornet's nest.
我刚下飞机就被克格勃的人认出来了
I was made by the KGB from the moment my feet touched the ground.
他们甚至可能早就知道了我的身份
Maybe even before.
你早就知道了 对吗?
You knew that. Didn't you?
你也怀疑珀西瓦尔
You had your doubts about Percival.
所以你利用我去试探他
And you used me to shake him down.
洗耳恭听
Ready when you are.
嘿!是我!
It's me, it's me!
他死了
He's dead.
小望远镜死了
Spyglass is dead.
但你还活着
And you're alive.
你没听懂我的意思
You aren't listening to me.
他们知道了
They knew..
克格勃的人什么都知道了
The KGB knew everything.
我需要离开这里
I need to get across.
扬
Jan.
我本以为英国佬们能搞定这件事 结果搞得一团糟
I expected more out of the Brits, and a wild goatfuck.
我知道 抱歉了
I know, we're sorry.
不 等等 等一下 你们没在斯塔西安插人吗?
No wait, your lot don't have your own private stasi agent, do you?
可他们没一个有过目不忘的能力
Not one with a photographic memory.
我们得注意布劳顿
We need to get with Broughton.
了解那个计划的所有情况
Get on the same page.
我们需要那份名单
We need that list.
现在就要
Now more than ever.
布劳顿
Broughton.
她成功逃了出来
She made it out.
真的吗?
Really?
你知道吗
You know...
大卫 一个意大利美女曾经对我说过 大卫
Beautiful Italian girl once said to me, David...
你永远不能改变已经发生过的事情
You can't unfuck what's been fucked.
女人办事总拖后腿 对吧
Women are always getting in way of progress, aren't they?
今晚发生了一件所有德国人都不会相信的事
What no one in Germany believed possible has happened tonight...
柏林墙倒了 真的倒了
The wall is coming down, the wall is down.
从1961年起那面墙下就伴随着我们的生活
We are in there living with the wall since 1961 and...
所以 我觉得现在是时候推倒它了
I think now it's time to break the wall down, you know.
当那面墙粉碎时
The wall is crumbling.
这些年轻人都出生于柏林墙建成之后 他们用锤子敲猛力敲击墙面
The sledgehammers in the hands of men not born when it went up tear into it.
墙后的东德士兵还试图阻止
Behind it, the East German soldiers tried to stop...
高压水枪都出动了 西柏林人表现地很是坚决
water cannons were brought out, but the west Berliners were determined.
一个西柏林人喷洒香槟以示回应
One west Berliner sprayed champaigne back.
我很负责的告诉你 如果是我跟踪你
If I was to follow you, I mean, properly,
你永远都发现不了
You would never fucking know.
柏林人等了28年就为这一天
It is the moment Berliners have waited 28 years for.
甚至东德人都显得很兴奋
Even the East Germans seem exhilarated.
柏林墙的建立导致了千百人的死亡
A symbolic breach in the structure that cost hundreds of lives...
使得亲朋爱侣分离数十年 柏林墙的倒下极具历史意义
and separated friends, families and lovers for decades.
小望远镜死后 我在他的大衣口袋中找到了一个法国特高频发信装置
Found a French UHF device in my coat after Spyglass died.
现在我觉得这窃听器是珀西瓦尔放在我外套内的
I now believe it was Percival who planted it.
而且要让它看起来像拉萨尔做的
Made it look like Lasalle.
你为什么在这
Why are you here?
你得离开柏林
You need to leave Berlin.
没有了你的消息 我很担心
When I didn't here from you, I got worried.
别这么幼稚
How naive can you be?
我们选择了这种生活 德尔菲娜
We chose this life, Delphine.
这种生活只会有一种结局
This only ends one way.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们都进了他的圈套了
He set us both up.
在你能走的时候赶紧走
You have to leave while you can.
别低估我 珀西瓦尔
Don't underestimate me, Percival.
哦 拉萨尔 你要仔细听我说
Oh. Lasalle, listen to me very carefully!
你根本不知道你在跟谁打交道
You have no idea who you are dealing with...
你给我下套
You set me up.
得了吧 这游戏就是这么玩的
Come on now, this is the game.
我知道你的秘密 大卫
I know your secrets, David.
而且这个游戏我玩的 比你想象的要好
And I can play this game better than you think.
珀西瓦尔试图陷害我
Percival is trying to set me up.
你惊讶吗
Are you surprised?
并不
Not really.
特工之间的合作不过是虚与委蛇
These relationships aren't real.
只是为完成任务的手段罢了
They are just a means to an end.
当你讲真话时 你看起来不一样了
When you tell the truth, you look different.
你的眼神变了
Your eyes change.
谢谢你提醒我
Thanks for the warning.
什么意思?  我的意思是我不会再犯这样的错了
What do you mean? I mean I better not do it again.
为什么?
Why?
因为将来有一天 我可能会为之丧命
Because it's going to get me killed one day.
我有些事情需要告诉你
There's something that I need to tell you.
一定和你的朋友珀西瓦尔有关吧
It has to do with your friend Percival.
他...
He...
对不起 亲爱的
Sorry darling!
这就是游戏规则
This is the game.
我去
Fuck!
今晚的街道上庆典将会继续
The celebrations continue in the streets tonight...
从第一波东德人穿过柏林墙开始
from the moment of first wave of East Germans crossing through Berlin
数千人喝着香槟 一起狂欢
They have been showered with champagne and cheered by a crowd of thousands.
很明显 这将会是东德最激动人心的日子之一
It is clear. This will be one of Berlin's most dramatic days.
当西柏林人从边境涌入时 东柏林人显得十分热情
East Berliners are overcome as they cross the border..
这条边境整整封闭了28年
That has been closed to them for 28 years.
西柏林人凿穿了那面荼毒了他们城市的墙 然后推倒了它
West Berliners are chipping through wall that scar their city and scaling it.
警察再也不会来干涉他们了
There is no more interfarence from the police.
东西柏林人和平地团结在了一起
Unified Berliners laced up with the peace
数千名示威名着魔似的呼喊着“再无柏林墙”
Thousands of the mutinees, enchanting it, "Down with the wall."
所以现在只有一个问题
So only one question after you ask...
这次事件中 到底谁才是真正的胜利者
Who won?
这所谓的游戏到底是什么
And what was the fucking game anyway?
我曾以为这面墙永远不会倒呢
I was thinking the wall will never fall...
德国的和平变革
Germany's peaceful revolution..
要想赢的话
To win...
首先你必须明确你的立场
First you have to know which side you are on..
在我们的工作中
In our line of work...
有许多阴暗面
That's right up there with black holes.
追随你选择的道路一直到底
All to be or not to be.
你以为你在为正义而战 忽然有一天你清醒了
You fight the good fight and then one day you wake up..
你会意识到自己是撒旦的使者 不过在传播毁灭而已
And you realize that all you were was satan's little helper.
真是讽刺啊
Ironic.
新闻告诉公众 不会再有秘密了
The news will them there will be no more secrets.
但你和我都知道这不是真的
But you and I, we both know that's not true.
这个世界永远存在着秘密
The world is run on secrets.
拥有这份名单的人将拥有权利
Whoever has that list has power...
没有它 你不过就是另一个目标罢了
And without it, you're just another fucking target..
所以经历了这一切之后我又学到了什么吗
So what have I learned after all this time?
那所有的无眠之夜
After all those sleepless nights.
那些对朋友 对爱侣 甚至对自己的欺骗
Lying to friends, lovers, myself.
在这个扭曲的城镇玩这些扭曲的游戏
Playing this crooked game in this crooked town..
充满了恶意中伤和狡诈的谎言
Filled with backstabbers and full fledged lies.
我要告诉你 我在这所明白的 唯一一件事
I'll tell you what I've learned, one thing and one thing only.
我热爱着柏林
I fucking love Berlin!
你不必杀了她的
You didn't have to kill her.
在你做过那些事之后
You suddenly decided to develop a conscience
你怎么突然良心发现了
after all you've done.
希望你注意到 每一个跟你接触的人
Hope you noticed how everyone you get close to..
都以死亡收场...
Ends up fucking dead...
你把计划的细节透露给布雷莫维奇
You gave Bremovych the details of the plan.
你想借克格勃的手来干掉我
You wanted the KGB to take me out.
是啊  你太害怕了 不敢自己动手了
Yeah. You're too fucking scared to do it yourself.
如果这帮克格勃的废物把你搞定了
If those KGB pricks done their part.
那我现在就能受到女王的接见了
I'd be on my way to handjob with the queen by now.
我已经读过那份名单
I have read that list.
洛林
Lorraine.
原来你是这么淘气的女孩
Turns out you've been a very naughty girl.
小望远镜对我们来说是个累赘
Spyglass was a liability to us all.
我不能冒险让他留在你身边
I could not risk leaving him with you.
名单在哪 大卫
Where is the list, David?
不在我手上
I don't have it.
它正在前往军情六处的路上
It's enroute to MI6, where it belongs!
到现在你还打算撒谎吗
Are you going to lie to the very end?
真相与谎言
Truth and lies...
我们这样的人总是很难看出两者的区别
People like us don't know the difference.
不 我们知道它们的区别 大卫
No, we know the difference, David.
我们只是选择去无视它
We choose to ignore it.
不是吗 萨切尔同志
Isn't that right comrade Satchel?
原来你准备这么干
So that's how you make it work?
欺骗欺人者 其乐无穷
It's a double pleasure to deceive the deceiver.
干的漂亮
Well played.
你杀了大卫·珀西瓦尔
You killed David Percival.
詹姆斯·加斯科涅和大卫·珀西瓦尔
All the paperwork are in order
尸体和文件手续都准备好了
for the bodies of James Gascoigne and David Percival.
你杀了柏林情报站的负责人  一名宣誓效忠女皇陛下的特工
You killed our head of station, an officer of the crown.
你最好有确凿的证据和充足的理由
You better have hard proof and a damn good explanation.
你有什么资格来审判我?  我是你的上级
Who are you to judge my actions? I'm your superior.
我的上级
My superior..
这次任务和阻止冷战没有任何关系
This was never about stopping the war.
而是为了保住你的位置
...was about saving your ass.
我们在冷战中犯下的罪行 要是暴露出去
You couldn't bear the embarrassment
会让你十分难堪
of the sins that we committed in the Cold War.
我是多么愚蠢啊 竟然愿意为之卖命
And I was stupid enough to give my life for it.
好吧
Yes, well...
这就是你的工作 不是吗
That's your job, isn't it?
我完成了我的工作
I did my job.
虽然你在我的背后捅刀子 而且能力极其低下
Despite your backstabbers and your incompetence..
我完成了你搞不定的任务
I succeeded where you failed.
我把内部的叛徒 萨切尔 揪了出来
I uncovered your traitor Satchel.
给了唯一配得上他的结局
Brought him the only justice he deserved.
死亡
A bullet!
就在小望远镜被杀前一天珀西瓦尔见了布雷莫维奇
Percival meeting with Bremovych. The day before Spyglass was killed.
或许我们可以做一些准备
Maybe we can make some sort of arrangement
你要知道我是这里唯一一个能帮你拿到那份名单的人
..you've gotta know I am the only man in this town that can help you get that list.
我记住你了
Very impressive.
奉献 忠诚这些品质现如今都难能可贵
Dedication... loyality are rare thing these days.
欺骗欺骗者 其乐无穷
It is a double pleasure to deceive the deceiver.
成交吗
We have an deal?
那这位英国小姐怎么想的呢?
What about the British?
你信任格雷吗?   并不
Do you trust Gray? No.
那C呢?
What about C.?
C是个自大的哈巴狗
C is a arrogant lab dog
珀西瓦尔就是萨切尔
Percival was Satchel.
那名单在哪?
Where is the list?
名单在哪? 洛林
Where is the list, Lorraine?
我不知道
I don't know.
扯淡
Oh, bollocks.
首相最近可不会好过了
The Prime Minister's gonna have a difficult time with this.
我们决定隐瞒这个任务 布劳顿
We are choosing to burry this one, Broughton.
你的任务从未发生
Your mission never took place.
这段对话
This conversation...
也从未发生
It never happened.
我打算让你休假一段时间 立即生效
I am putting you on leave effective immidiately.
你会开始一段新生活 好好休息
You will start the next decade.. Well rested.
C...
C..
我该穿什么
What should I wear?
去和女王喝茶?
For my tea with the Queen?
你真的认为我会把名单给你?
Did you really think I was going to give you that list?
在你死前 我想让你那迟钝的脑袋明白
Before you die, I want to get this through your thick primitive skull.
我从未为你工作
I've never worked for you.
你却一直在为我卖命
You worked for me.
我给你的每一个假情报
Every false intel I gave you...
都在铁幕上撕开一道裂缝
A rip in the iron curtain.
你给我的每一个情报都化作我枪膛里的一颗子弹
Every piece of intel you gave me a bullet in my fucking gun.
我想好好过日子
I want my life back.
一路顺风
Safe travels.
航班预计在11小时37分钟之后抵达兰利市
Estimated flight time to Langley, 11 hours and 37 minutes
准备起飞
Clear to takeoff.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
听起来不错
That sounds good.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
你当时骂我浑蛋?
Cocksucker?
真的吗?
Really?
很不错 我们俩演的还挺像的
I'm glad it was convincing.